OLIVIA FAVOS

+61 403 412 190
livfavos@icloud.com
oliviafavos.com
linkedin.com/in/oliviafavos
github.com/lvfvs

Hi, I'm <u>Olivia!</u> Throughout my computer science degree and internships, I've cultivated a love for <u>web development</u>, and <u>UI/UX design</u>. I'm searching for a role where I can build beautiful, functional, and accessible experiences, driven by my skills in design and computer science. I have a proven ability to collaborate with peers to achieve common goals, I ambitiously apply creativity and logic to devlop solutions to the problems I encounter, and <u>I have a strong desire to grow</u>.

References available upon request.

EDUCATION

2018 – Present (Expected graduation 2023) Bachelor of Computer Science at the University of Newcastle

2015 Cert IV in Graphic Design at Shillington College

CAPABILITES

Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, various React component and testing libraries, Node.js, SQL, Java, C/C++, Git)

UI prototyping & design systems (Figma, Adobe Creative Suite: Id, Ps, Ai)

LANGUAGES

English (Native)
Japanese (Conversational)

EXPERIENCE

Apr 2022 – Oct 2022 Consultation Manager Intern Software Developer

- * Contributed to the implementation of Consultation Manager's new design system for their web application, which involved developing extensible and reliable components using TypeScript in a React framework, supported by the Chakra UI React component library.
- * Resolved tickets, including bug fixes and improvements to existing product features, using Angular.
- * Engaged in test-driven development to build solutions using Jest, which helped to prevent avoidable bugs and ensured the reliability and speed of our application.
- * Communicated and implemented design solutions to existing problems, providing a more functional and appealing product for end-users.
- * Actively participated in Agile workflows, sprint planning, and retrospectives.

Apr 2022 - Nov 2022

Mudbath

Student Intern

- * Designed and developed a middleware, 'Hashi', for the company using JavaScript and React, built using the Mantine React component library.
- * Implemented basic routing using Node.js within an Express.js framework.
- * Used Figma to design a high-fidelity prototype of 'Hashi', designing the UI to align with client needs.

May 2019 - Apr 2022

Apple

Technical Specialist → Technical Expert

- * Provided mentorship, feedback, and education to technical specialists on technical and customer service issues.
- * Performed repair on iOS devices.
- * Worked within team environments demonstrating shared responsibility and accountability with other team members.
- * Resolved an extensive range of customer service issues, navigating interactions with empathy and creative problem solving.
- * Explained difficult technical issues in simple terms, and enabled customers to select the best solution to meet their needs.
- * Handled escalating customer service issues with composure and confidence.
- * Supported customers in a timely manner, effectively balancing priorities under tight deadlines
- * Thrived in a collaborative and dynamic team environment, achieving both individual and team productivity goals.